Vanessa Azenwa Shiundu

vanessa.azenwa@gmail.com / +254717400821 / Nairobi, Kenya

Summary

Title: Fullstack Software Developer

I am a talented Junior Software Engineer trained to work with customers, team members and project leaders to accomplish software engineering and updating tasks according to timelines.

With a solid understanding of full development lifecycle, skilled to work with front and back-end technologies to produce and evaluate projects, I look forward to joining a dynamic team and contribute towards providing creative solutions and making the world a better place; one day at a time.

In addition, I have industry specific training and experience in IT, Statistics and Finance. View My LinkedIn Profile and My GitHub Profile for a sample of the applications and websites I have built over the past few months.

Skills

Django, Flask, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Google Cloud Platform, APIs, Git, Databases, SQL, PostgreSQL, Flutter, Python, Angular

Education

Software Engineering

Moringa School • Nairobi 07/2022

Diploma in Business and Accounting

ACCA 10/2016

Digital Marketing

Google and Livity Africa 06/2015

Dlploma in French

Alliance Française de Nairobi 11/2014

Statistics and Statistical Packages

University of Nairobi 10/2013

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

St. Theresea's Eregi 11/2011 A-

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

St. Teresa's Isanjiro 11/2007

Α

Experience

Software Developer

01/2022 - Present

- Efficient collaboration with team members and leading a number of projects as SCRUM MASTER.
- Designing the structure of websites and apps, optimizing for mobile devices
- Creating the logic that instructs applications on how to interpret user input and what feedback to give the user after executing the submitted request I achieved this by creating algorithms that fetch and manipulate data stored in database systems mainly using python, Flask, Django, Flutter and SQL.
- Developing app integration with REST APIs for google maps, social media authentication, movie APIs and other services.
- Proficient in Git and Git-hub for version control
- · Managing time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades
- Planning, writing and debugging web applications and software with complete accuracy.

Finance Assistant

Vivo Energy Kenya 03/2019 - 03/2020

- Within established guidelines, prepare weekly and monthly financial analysis reports and provide advice to management
- Assist Project Manager with project setup, project monitoring, system updating and closeout; Monitor projects for contract compliance
- · Perform business and financial analysis and prepare reports upon request for management review
- · Assist in maintaining, tracking and ensuring compliance of confidential company contracts with external parties
- Monitoring and maintenance of customer master data, including customer account management and payments
- Review of Retail convenience shop vendor invoices for appropriate documentation and approval prior to payment
- Perform bank account reconciliations
- Prepare reports for review and analysis to maintain operational & business trend analysis in addition to reporting for shop sales, fuel & other petroleum products sales; thereafter assist management in developing financial analysis, reporting, and budgeting
- · Validating financial data, modifying, and scheduling reports to assist with business intelligence
- Support/backup other team mates in the various departmental functions
- Understand and actively participate in HSSE (Health, Safety, Security & Environment) responsibilities
- Manage & prepare customer aging analysis between SAP vs VAT invoices
- Timely process statutory accounting requirements including Withholding Vat, Fuel VAT and related Statutory requirements
- Resolve questions and problems arising from these functions and more
- Provide operational support during Stock Take
- Thoroughly performed Station Audit for 1 station
- · Perform other duties as assigned

Intern cum Retail Stations Assistant

Engen Kenya Itd

04/2017 - 02/2019

- Review of Convenience shop vendor invoices for appropriate documentation and approval prior to payment
- · Compile and Analyse monthly output and input VAT
- Daily monitor and reconcile the Retail Stations' Dashboards
- Process instructions to banks for issuing banker's cheques
- Offer guidance to stations' accountants on vigilance to prevent fraudulent activity from dishonest vendors
- Provide operational support during Stock Take

- Reconcile Monthly stations' data with SAP movements
- Thoroughly performed Station Audit for 3 stations
- Handling petty cash and related transactions when needed
- Maintain files of financial records and confidential contracts
- Prepare weekly and monthly financial reports and provide advice to management
- · Perform administrative duties for Finance Manager
- · Diarize credit and supplier meetings
- Minute taking of Company suppliers' credit meetings
- · Understand and actively participate in HSEQ (Health, Safety, Environment & Quality) responsibilities
- Provide administrative assistance for other Classes of Business Managers as needed from the Finance function.

Reliever Church Accountant

Nairobi East SDA Church

11/2021 - 12/2021

I contributed to the Financial Management of the institution by:

- · Reviewing of service provider & vendor invoices for appropriate documentation and
- · approval prior to payment
- Processing bank, cheque and M-Pesa payments of all expenses and bills
- Maintain files of confidential financial records
- Prepare financial reports and provide advice to Treasurer
- Managing petty cash and related transactions
- Perform weekly cash, M-Pesa and bank account reconciliations

English, French, Swahili

References

1. Stanley Njuru,

Treasurer,

Vivo Energy Kenya ltd.

2. Joshua Aura,

ACCA Lecturer, Regional Centre of Management.

3. Dr Isaac Kipchirchir C.

School of Mathematics,

University of Nairobi,

4. Philip Migire,

Treasurer - Nairobi East SDA,

· Contact details available upon request